<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<root>
  <displayName>Jack</displayName>
  <needsItemId>null</needsItemId>
  <dataBlock>
    <id>Village.xml</id>
    <currentDialogue>0</currentDialogue>
    <currentDescription>0</currentDescription>
    <currentDetailedDescription>0</currentDetailedDescription>
    <description skipIf="numVisitsGreaterThan 1">A boy dashes out of the #woods^, returning to the #village^. He freezes in play when he spots you.
    
Boy: You— You're the man that rescued me from the Wicked Witch all those years ago. You're Geralt, aren't you?  It's me, #Jack^.  I need your help again.

To @talk^ to #Jack^, type "talk jack" and hit ENTER.

If you need a @hint^, type either "hint" or "help" and hit ENTER.</description>
    <description>#Jack^ follows you, but is unwilling to leave the #woods^ and Joss behind.</description>
    <detailedDescription skipIf="numVisitsGreaterThan 1">Jack looks desperate, gasping in panic-breaths.</detailedDescription>
    <detailedDescription>#Jack^ looks uneasy about returning to the #village^.</detailedDescription>
    <dialogue skipIf="numVisitsGreaterThan 1">Another witch has come to haunt these #woods^, and Joss is missing. He may be a rotten old soul, but he's a neighbor.  If we just let her have him, who knows whom she'll make off with next?  Follow me.  We need to @go^ back into the #woods^ to find Joss.

To @go^ into the #woods^, type 'go woods' and hit ENTER.</dialogue>
    <dialogue>We should @go^ back to the #woods^ to look for Joss.</dialogue>
  </dataBlock>
  <dataBlock>
    <id>Woods.xml</id>
    <currentDialogue>0</currentDialogue>
    <currentDescription>0</currentDescription>
    <currentDetailedDescription>0</currentDetailedDescription>
    <description>#Jack^ leads you on, being careful not to get too far ahead of you.
	
Jack: "I heard the howls of wolves two nights ago coming from these woods. I haven't seen Joss since that afternoon.  I've been looking for a sign, but nothing seems to point to where he might be.  Perhaps a witcher like you could @check^ out the surroundings and find a clue."

To @check^ something out, type "check" followed by the name of the thing you want to @check^ and hit ENTER.

To @check^ the #bushes^, type "check bushes" and hit ENTER.</description>
    <detailedDescription>He looks around at the tree tops.</detailedDescription>
    <dialogue>Don't look at me!  I've been searching for a sign all day.</dialogue>
  </dataBlock>
  <dataBlock>
    <id>DeepWoods.xml</id>
    <currentDialogue>0</currentDialogue>
    <currentDescription>0</currentDescription>
    <currentDetailedDescription>0</currentDetailedDescription>
    <description>#Jack^ is caught in the thorns.
    
Jack: "Ouch!  I can't make it any further. Here, @take^ my #torch^.  You can @use^ it to light up dark places."

To @take^ the #torch^, type "take torch" and hit ENTER.</description>
    <detailedDescription>He is too weak to make it through the thorns.</detailedDescription>
    <detailedDescription>Jack returns to the village.</detailedDescription>
    <dialogue>I'm going back to the village.  I'll leave it to you to find Joss.</dialogue>
  </dataBlock>
  <dataBlock>
    <id>Ending.xml</id>
    <currentDescription>0</currentDescription>
    <currentDetailedDescription>0</currentDetailedDescription>
    <currentDialogue>0</currentDialogue>
    <description>It is the figure of a boy. #Jack^ is standing before the portal.
	
Jack: I see you are weary, but we must @talk^.</description>
    <detailedDescription skipIf="isInParty joss">He looks horrified.</detailedDescription>
    <detailedDescription skipIf="QisInParty wolf">He looks nervous.</detailedDescription>
    <detailedDescription skipIf="isInParty mother">He looks worried.</detailedDescription>
    <detailedDescription>He looks relieved.</detailedDescription>
	<dialogue skipIf="isInParty joss">Geralt, where is Joss? You did not leave him behind, did you? No one can survive that burning. The White Wolf has slain a witch but cursed a young man to death in return. This #portal^ will not send you far away from your misdeeds, but will instead give you a chance to atone for them. @Go^ through the #portal^ if you would not carry Joss's death on your shoulders for the rest of your days.</dialogue>
    <dialogue skipIf="!isInParty wolf">Joss! You are safe! The White Wolf has slain the witch.

Joss: The grey wolf and the White Wolf have saved me.

Jack: Glad am I to hear that, but did either save your mother? For a beast drag her from the edge of town this night. She was dragged deep into the forest where that pyre now burns.

Geralt: Could that have been the woman beyond the red gate?

Joss: No one can survive that burning!  And all to spare this #wolf^.

Jack: This #portal^ will not send you far away from this fate, but will instead give you a chance to avoid it.  @Go^ through the #portal^ if you would not carry this death on your shoulders for the rest of your days.</dialogue>
    <dialogue skipIf="isInParty mother">Joss! You are safe! The White Wolf has slain the witch.

Joss: In that I take but little cheer.  He has also slain my dear protect.

Jack: Say not your 'dear protect' was your dear mother!  For a beast drag her from the edge of town this night.

Geralt: Of course I did not slay his mother.  Where did they go?

Jack: She was dragged deep into the forest where that pyre now burns.

Joss: She was the woman beyond the red gate!  No one can survive that burning. My protector and my mother you have taken from me.

Jack: This #portal^ will not send you far away from your misdeeds, but will instead give you a chance to atone for them.  @Go^ through the #portal^ if you would not carry these deaths on your shoulders for the rest of your days.</dialogue>
    <dialogue>Joss! You are safe! But your mother—

Joss's mother: Is well, or will be after some rest. The White Wolf has slain the witch.

Joss: Jack, will you help us to our house. Mother needs a proper bed.

Jack: Of course I will. Geralt, we have not the means to repay you for all your service. If you would know what other fates may have befallen these folk had you acted otherwise, this #portal^ will give you a chance to write a new history.  @Go^ through the #portal^ if you would change the outcome of this night.</dialogue>
  </dataBlock>
</root>