<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<root>
  <displayName>Joss</displayName>
  <needsItemId>whipFromBasement</needsItemId>
  <dataBlock>
    <id>Basement.xml</id>
    <currentDescription>0</currentDescription>
    <currentDetailedDescription>0</currentDetailedDescription>
    <currentDialogue>0</currentDialogue>
    <description skipIf="!isInParty wolf">The boy is indeed #Joss^. He has grown much in the past few years.</description>
    <description skipIf="isInParty mother">#Joss^ throws himself upon the newly slain wolf.</description>
    <description>#Joss^ is following you closely and supporting his #mother^.</description>
    <detailedDescription skipIf="!isInParty wolf">His sour attitude seems diminished. The terror of the #nekker^ and the support of the #wolf^ may have caused a change in him.</detailedDescription>
    <detailedDescription skipIf="isInParty mother">He is filled with despair and spite.</detailedDescription>
    <detailedDescription>He holds up his #mother^'s weight, her arm pulled over his shoulders.</detailedDescription>
    <dialogue skipIf="!isInParty wolf">Can it be you? First this grey #wolf^ and now the White Wolf come to my aid! I am Joss, and I beg you to forgive me for my misleading words I spoke to you at our last meeting. I have been shaken to my core, and have grown because of it.

Geralt: Good. So you can give me the truth, and all the truth. Are you alone down here?

Joss: I have this #wolf^ with me. I followed him and his mate to the clearing in the woods. I thought they would kill me when they finally spotted me, but then that monster appeared from the hut and chased us down here. A can't tell you how many days ago that was.

Geralt: What can you tell me?

Joss: That the wolves hated the monster more than they hated me. And that this is a witch's hut! That monster obeys her and watches us. She killed the second wolf tonight to open the #gate^. She threw some poor woman in there. I covered my face when the witch came, but I think the woman my have come from my own village.

Geralt: A sacrifice to open the #gate^, huh?

Joss: I suppose, but you mustn't hurt this #wolf^. He has saved my life.</dialogue>
    <dialogue skipIf="isInParty mother">How could you? You are a monster yourself.

Geralt: The gate needed a sacrifice. The nekker didn't cut it. It was either the wolf or you.

Joss: Whoever's through that gate can't be worth the life of this wolf.</dialogue>
    <dialogue>My #mother^ is weak.  We must get her home so she can rest.</dialogue>
  </dataBlock>
  <dataBlock>
    <id>Subbasement.xml</id>
    <currentDescription>0</currentDescription>
    <currentDetailedDescription>0</currentDetailedDescription>
    <currentDialogue>0</currentDialogue>
    <description skipIf="isInParty mother">#Joss^ seeing the woman cries out at once, "#Mother^!"</description>
    <description>#Joss^ catches his #mother^ as she begins to slump down when the bonds release her.</description>
    <detailedDescription skipIf="isInParty mother">He pulls fruitlessly at the iron #bonds^.</detailedDescription>
    <detailedDescription>He holds up his #mother^'s weight, her arm pulled over his shoulders.</detailedDescription>
    <dialogue skipIf="playerHas key + !isInParty mother">It's my #mother^! We need to unlock her #bonds^.</dialogue>
    <dialogue skipIf="isInParty mother">Here, Geralt. Unlock the #bonds^.</dialogue>
    <dialogue>My #mother^ is weak.  We must get her home so she can rest.</dialogue>
  </dataBlock>
  <dataBlock>
    <id>Hall.xml</id>
    <currentDescription>0</currentDescription>
    <currentDetailedDescription>0</currentDetailedDescription>
    <currentDialogue>0</currentDialogue>
    <description skipIf="!isInParty wolf">#Joss^ pets the wolf nervously on the head.</description>
    <description skipIf="isInParty mother">#Joss^ casts his eyes to the floor.</description>
    <description>#Joss^ is following you closely and supporting his #mother^.</description>
    <detailedDescription skipIf="!isInParty wolf">He looks afraid to go on and even more afraid to go back.</detailedDescription>
    <detailedDescription skipIf="isInParty mother">He is hunched and rigid, teeming with spite.</detailedDescription>
    <detailedDescription>He holds up his #mother^'s weight, her arm pulled over his shoulders.</detailedDescription>
    <dialogue skipIf="!isInParty wolf">Let's get out of here.  Lead the way.</dialogue>
    <dialogue skipIf="isInParty mother">You killed him.  And all for no reason.  Bring me out of this horrid hut that I might depart from you forever.</dialogue>
    <dialogue>My #mother^ is weak.  We must get her home so she can rest.</dialogue>
  </dataBlock>
  <dataBlock>
    <id>WitchsHut.xml</id>
    <currentDescription>0</currentDescription>
    <currentDetailedDescription>0</currentDetailedDescription>
    <currentDialogue>0</currentDialogue>
    <description skipIf="!isInParty wolf">#Joss^ clings to the #wolf^ with one arm.</description>
    <description skipIf="isInParty mother">#Joss^ glares at you.</description>
    <description>#Joss^ pulls his #mother^ through the trap door.</description>
    <detailedDescription skipIf="!isInParty wolf">He is nearest to the trap door.</detailedDescription>
    <detailedDescription skipIf="isInParty mother">He clenches the rungs of the #ladder^ below you.</detailedDescription>
    <detailedDescription>He crouches low, pulling his #mother^'s arm over his shoulder.</detailedDescription>
    <dialogue skipIf="!isInParty wolf">(whispering) Kill the devil.</dialogue>
    <dialogue skipIf="isInParty mother">I know not which of you I despise more.</dialogue>
    <dialogue>(whispering) Hurry, Geralt. Do something about the witch.</dialogue>
  </dataBlock>
  <dataBlock>
    <id>Ending.xml</id>
    <currentDescription>0</currentDescription>
    <currentDetailedDescription>0</currentDetailedDescription>
    <currentDialogue>0</currentDialogue>
    <description>>#Joss^ stops before the figure.</description>
    <detailedDescription>He is out of breath.</detailedDescription>
    <dialogue skipIf="!isInParty wolf">It's the village!
	
Jack: Joss! You are safe! The White Wolf has slain the witch.

Joss: The grey wolf and the White Wolf have saved me.

Jack: Glad am I to hear that, but did either save your mother? For a beast drag her from the edge of town this night. She was dragged deep into the forest where that pyre now burns.

Geralt: Could that have been the woman beyond the red gate?

Joss: No one can survive that burning!  And all to spare this #wolf^.

Jack: This #portal^ will not send you far away from this fate, but will instead give you a chance to avoid it.  @Go^ through the #portal^ if you would not carry this death on your shoulders for the rest of your days.</dialogue>
    <dialogue skipIf="isInParty mother">Well, we have reached the village.

Jack: Joss! You are safe! The White Wolf has slain the witch.

Joss: In that I take but little cheer.  He has also slain my dear protect.

Jack: Say not your 'dear protect' was your dear mother!  For a beast drag her from the edge of town this night.

Geralt: Of course I did not slay his mother.  Where did they go?

Jack: She was dragged deep into the forest where that pyre now burns.

Joss: She was the woman beyond the red gate!  No one can survive that burning. My protector and my mother you have taken from me.

Jack: This #portal^ will not send you far away from your misdeeds, but will instead give you a chance to atone for them.  @Go^ through the #portal^ if you would not carry these deaths on your shoulders for the rest of your days.</dialogue>
    <dialogue>We've nearly made it, Mother.

Jack: Joss! You are safe! But your mother—

Joss's mother: Is well, or will be after some rest. The White Wolf has slain the witch.

Joss: Jack, will you help us to our house. Mother needs a proper bed.

Jack: Of course I will. Geralt, we have not the means to repay you for all your service. If you would know what other fates may have befallen these folk had you acted otherwise, this #portal^ will give you a chance to write a new history.  @Go^ through the #portal^ if you would change the outcome of this night.</dialogue>
  </dataBlock>
</root>