<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<root>

<description>A guide has lead you and twelve other children to a clearing in the forest.
Though it is still early in the day, the sun shines through the clouds,
and its rays are warm on your face.  The leaves of the trees are thick,
and the world is dark beneath them.
    
Your guide speaks, "You have all done well in following me through this
tangled wood.  Now we come to the point in your training where you will
no longer follow, but will lead yourselves.  Be aware of your surroundings
and you will find your way, wherever your way may go.  Look diligently for
signs that will guide down a sure path. Examine the various thing you find."
    
You learned the examine command!
Type "examine" and then the name of what you want to take a closer look at.
Then hit ENTER.
Example:  examine guide
</description>

  <exit>
    <keyword>south</keyword>
    <description>To the south, there is a slight gap in the trees encircling the clearing.</description>
    <detailedDescription>Though you could easily walk through the gap, the path appears to have seen little use.
Whisps of fog linger deep within.</detailedDescription>
    <destination>GameData/GapInTrees.xml</destination>
    <isLocked>false</isLocked>
  </exit>

  <prop>
    <keyword>guide</keyword>
    <description>Your guide stands near the gap in the trees.</description>
    <detailedDescription>Your guide is clad in leather armor and a dark green cloak.
He speaks, "Well done. Now explore your surrounds and move through the forest.
Go to new areas."

You learned the go command!
Type "go" and then the name of the you want to follow.
Then hit ENTER.
Example:  go south</detailedDescription>
  </prop>

  <prop>
    <keyword>children</keyword>
    <description>The other children in your group are listening to the guide.</description>
    <detailedDescription>There are 12 other children in your group.  Some look confident, others nervous, but all are happy to see the sun.</detailedDescription>
  </prop>

</root>