<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<root>

  <description>The rotting, wooden door creaks as you push it open.
You are in a narrow hall lit by torches.</description>

  <exit>
    <keyword>north</keyword>
    <description>To the north, stairs lead upward.</description>
    <detailedDescription>The stairs are made of stone slabs.  The air above is foul.</detailedDescription>
    <destination>GameData/DungeonEntrance.xml</destination>
    <isLocked>false</isLocked>
  </exit>

  <exit>
    <keyword>east</keyword>
    <description>To the east, the door to your dungeon cell is open.</description>
    <detailedDescription>The rotting, wooden door hangs on rope hinges.  The fastening rope has been cut,
and hangs from a hook on the wall.</detailedDescription>
    <destination>GameData/Cell_Player.xml</destination>
    <isLocked>false</isLocked>
  </exit>

  <exit>
    <keyword>south</keyword>
    <description>To the south, stairs lead downward.</description>
    <detailedDescription>The stairs are made of stone slabs.
The air is chill, but touchligh can be seen at the lower landing.</detailedDescription>
    <destination>GameData/Dungeon_B2.xml</destination>
    <isLocked>false</isLocked>
  </exit>

  <exit>
    <keyword>west</keyword>
    <description>To the west, there is a closed door.  A lock holds the door closed.</description>
    <detailedDescription>The door build of solid wood and its hinges are iron.
Pressing your ear to the door, you hear whimpering within.</detailedDescription>
    <destination>GameData/TBD.xml</destination>
    <isLocked>true</isLocked>
  </exit>

  <prop>
    <keyword>walls</keyword>
    <description>The walls are of grey stone.</description>
    <detailedDescription> Large stones are press into the wet, dirt walls.  At each door, the stone are
scratched and stained.</detailedDescription>
  </prop>

  <prop>
    <keyword>floor</keyword>
    <description>The floor is of uneven, but solid dirt.</description>
    <detailedDescription>It has seen much use and has been pressed solid by heavy boots.</detailedDescription>
  </prop>

  <prop>
    <keyword>creature</keyword>
    <description>A grey and hairy creature clad in rusted mail is sprawled out, motionless on the ground.</description>
    <detailedDescription>The creature lies in a stinking black pool of blood.  Its yellow eyes and its
jaws of dagger-like teeth are open, but the creature is dead.
Its gloved fingers are long and tipped with bony claws.  This must be a goblin.</detailedDescription>
  </prop>

  <prop>
    <keyword>guide</keyword>
    <description>Your guide is doubled over near the locked door.</description>
    <detailedDescription>His flesh is pale and his face cast down.  He is dead.</detailedDescription>
  </prop>

</root>